<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Harrisonburg Real Estate Video Blog with Brad Cohen</title>
    <description>Our mission at Harman Realty is to be your best resource for Harrisonburg real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Harman Realty, your professional Harrisonburg Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 11:52:37 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 11:52:37 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>I’m Here for You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9MjuYybpXc4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s message is simple: I’m here for you during these challenging times. Whether you need real estate advice, financial advice, personal advice, or just a quick favor, my entire network is at your disposal. Times are hard, but we’ll get through this together. To see my full message, watch this short video. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 09:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/im-here-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/im-here-for-you.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Never Before Have We Seen This Type of Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qSr-iyx9cYY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Our market is unprecedented right now, and it&amp;rsquo;s a great time to buy or sell.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’re experiencing in our market is unprecedented. Never before have we had such a strong seller’s market while simultaneously experiencing such good buying conditions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of the recording of this video, we have 34 active listings in Harrisonburg and 173 in Rockingham County. We’ve talked a lot about declining inventory the past two years or so, so it’s time to put this into a historical context. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With just 34 active listings, based on last year’s annual pace of sales, if there was no new inventory introduced to the market, we’d sell out in the &lt;em&gt;next month&lt;/em&gt;. Rockingham County isn’t much different—they only have a two-month supply of homes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of unprecedented, let’s talk about rates. Last week, the rate for a 30-year fixed-rate mortgage dropped down to 3%. The last time we even got close to this mark was in 2016, and back then we didn’t have the extreme disparity between buyers and sellers that we do now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Never before have we had such a strong seller’s market while simultaneously experiencing such good buying conditions.%20http://localhost:4000/never-before-have-we-seen-this-type-of-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Never before have we had such a strong seller’s market while simultaneously experiencing such good buying conditions.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When rates drop, affordability increases for most buyers, which creates a surge of buyer activity. If you’re a buyer, this means you’ll face more competition—especially with dwindling inventory. If you’re a seller, you’ll likely see a surge in showing activity and get offers quickly. &lt;strong&gt;With inventory dwindling to what I consider a dangerous level and buyer activity surging, now is the time to sell.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers may be frustrated with the lack of supply, but there will be more, and knowing that rates are as low as they’ve ever been, &lt;strong&gt;it’s also a good time to buy.&lt;/strong&gt; As prices rise and rates go down, affordability generally stays the same. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These conditions make it even more important to work with an agent who has their finger on the pulse of the market and has all the latest information. It may result in you being the one winning out in a bidding war, or generating a bidding war for your home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about our Harrisonburg market or need help buying or selling, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 12:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/never-before-have-we-seen-this-type-of-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/never-before-have-we-seen-this-type-of-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Essential Info for Harrisonburg Homebuyers and Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8xFDa-Px2jI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a look at the latest numbers, and I have important advice to share with homebuyers and sellers in the Harrisonburg area. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know about the 2020 market.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we know it, the spring market will be upon us. If you are thinking about buying or selling in 2020, now is the time for us to get together to plan for it, and here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For home sellers, being early to market is going to give you a win this spring.&lt;/strong&gt; We do not need to be waiting until late March or April to get your house on the market. That may end up backfiring. There has been a major uptick in new housing starts, and competition for sellers this spring and summer may be stronger than what we have seen all of last year. Right now is the time for us to meet, get eyes on your property, and talk about any preparations it needs before putting it on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to do a small bathroom renovation or get a fresh coat of paint put on before selling, now is the time to be making those arrangements before contractors get too busy. I can provide you with quality insights on what to do to get maximum ROI once I get eyes on your property. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, your house does not need to be in “show-ready” condition for me to come look at it the first time. I promise I won’t judge you — nobody lives in a home the way it looks on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s never too early to get your financing in order.%20http://localhost:4000/essential-info-for-harrisonburg-homebuyers-and-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s never too early to get your financing in order.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For buyers, I know it seems rough right now and like there is nothing on the market. That’s normal for this time of year. &lt;strong&gt;Get ready, though, because that is going to change fast&lt;/strong&gt;. Now is the time for us to be meeting to plan your process if you are thinking about buying in 2020. Getting together allows us to plan out your timeline and make sure financing is in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timelines are also important.&lt;/strong&gt; If your lease is up in June, we want to make sure we are actively looking by April to allow enough time to close (30 to 60 days). It’s never too early to start getting financing in order either so you are ready to make an offer when the perfect home hits the market (which could be tomorrow).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get your taxes done. That refund could be a great jumpstart to your down payment or closing costs. By the way, rates are still historically low. Despite prices being up, affordability has not changed dramatically. &lt;strong&gt;Now is the time for us to be meeting to plan out your process.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is, no matter whether you’re buying or selling, let’s get together now and start talking about a plan for the fast-approaching spring market. Call/text/email me or hit me up in the comments. I’m here to help. Also, please send this message onward to someone you know who needs to hear it! I love seeing my videos get shared!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 10:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/essential-info-for-harrisonburg-homebuyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/essential-info-for-harrisonburg-homebuyers-and-sellers.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Smaller Homes Are Becoming More Popular</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RhZ5EP2iQqo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Why are smaller homes becoming more and more popular? Find out today.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, we’ve noticed that smaller homes are becoming increasingly popular among homebuyers. Why is that, though?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand this trend, first &lt;strong&gt;look to the younger generations of buyers, meaning Gen Z and millennials.&lt;/strong&gt; These age groups are trending toward more urban, higher-density homes that provide greater access to amenities. Due to this, we’ve noticed a rise in planned communities with a lot of mixed-use (i.e., residential and commercial) spaces in the same area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Older generations are looking for smaller, lower-maintenance properties as well. They’re looking for increased accessibility in their homes, ideally with fewer stairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=People are trending away from larger homes to spare themselves the effort of cleaning and maintaining all that square footage.%20http://localhost:4000/smaller-homes-are-becoming-more-popular.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“People are trending away from larger homes to spare themselves the effort of cleaning and maintaining all that square footage.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two demographics are the largest segments of the market, which is likely why you’re seeing new construction home size trending downward. In 2019, only 20% of the homes we sold in total were 2,500 square feet or greater, and 93% of new construction homes were below that size threshold. &lt;strong&gt;The largest percentage of the market is looking for homes between 1,500 and 2,500 square feet.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, I think that people are trending away from larger homes to spare themselves the effort of cleaning and maintaining all that square footage. Smaller homes prevent them from becoming house-poor and allow them to invest some of their money into experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I expect to see this trend continue in our market as we advance into the new decade.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have any questions about this trend or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 09:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/smaller-homes-are-becoming-more-popular.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/smaller-homes-are-becoming-more-popular.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Predictions for the 2020 Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BsxwIf8I1KI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m sharing what respected authorities like the National Association of Realtors and the Mortgage Bankers Association are predicting for 2020.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the tail of an interesting 2019, I’m going to give a forecast for the real estate market in 2020. Here’s what experts are predicting: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mortgage interest rates are expected to remain low.&lt;/strong&gt; Experts from Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, NAR, and the Mortgage Bankers Association are predicting that rates should remain fairly stable throughout 2020—great news for buyers looking to capitalize on the lowest rates we’ve seen in history (all under 4%). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite dwindling inventory, three of the four experts I just mentioned are predicting an increase in sales. Thanks to those low rates, buyer demand is still high, and with the uptick of new construction in our area, we expect to see more sales. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I’m very optimistic about this year.%20http://localhost:4000/4-predictions-for-the-2020-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I’m very optimistic about this year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six of the expert entities that keep track of home prices are all predicting an increase in prices throughout 2020—quite in line with what we saw in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A recession isn’t likely, and if it does occur here, it won’t be severe.&lt;/strong&gt; Last year, the number of forecasters predicting a 2020 recession was significant, but more recently, it has gone down quite a bit. No one knows for certain what will happen, but the experts do agree that, should a recession happen this year, its effect on the real estate market will be minimal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very optimistic about this year. I’ve got a lot on my queue and more people are reaching out to me every day. You may recall that I recently sent out a survey. 14% of respondents said they will buy or sell a house in 2020, while 42% said they plan to do a remodel this year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need any recommendations for contractors or builders, or have any questions about the market, feel free to call or email me. I’d be happy to help any way I can. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 09:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-predictions-for-the-2020-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-predictions-for-the-2020-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Should You Break the “Five-Year Rule” of Homeownership?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CH9nTO4ra5I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Generally, homeowners shouldn&amp;rsquo;t sell for at least five years. However, here are three exceptions to that rule.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own your home, or have ever thought about buying one, it’s important to know about the “five-year rule.” Essentially, it’s a widely-accepted concept that you shouldn’t sell your home until you’ve owned it for at least five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, if you sell a home within five years of buying it, you probably won’t recoup the costs from that sale. You may even end up having to bring money to the table. However, there are three notable exceptions to this rule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The property values in your neighborhood start to skyrocket.&lt;/strong&gt; If you can time the market really well or if there’s a crazy demand for homes in your neighborhood, then that’s the time to sell. This is exactly why I’m selling my home right now. I only bought it two years ago, but the neighborhood has been built out since and I’m already sitting on a lot of equity. I should be able to walk away from the sale and put a good amount of the profit I make into my renovation project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Not everything that you dislike about your home can be fixed with renovations.%20http://localhost:4000/when-should-you-break-the-five-year-rule-of-homeownership.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Not everything that you dislike about your home can be fixed with renovations.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The property values in your neighborhood start to plummet.&lt;/strong&gt; We aren’t really seeing this in our market right now, but it’s something you should be aware of. If prices start to drop dramatically in your neighborhood, it might be a good idea to sell now before prices get so low that you can’t sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You have a change in your lifestyle or mentality.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’ve gone through a job relocation, divorce, or you’re simply unhappy with the space, it’s not worth compromising your happiness to stay in the house. While many things that you dislike about your house can be fixed with renovations, not everything can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what certain renovations might cost or if you’re curious about what you can sell your home for right now, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 13:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/when-should-you-break-the-five-year-rule-of-homeownership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/when-should-you-break-the-five-year-rule-of-homeownership.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buying a Home Doesn’t Have to Break the Bank</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zqdQgAjfp44?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much does a Harrisonburg home really cost? Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people are unclear about what it really costs to buy a home. Fortunately, the total expenses of this purchase can be broken down into two categories: upfront expenses and cash to close, both of which we’ll break down for you today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we do that, though, let me share an interesting fact: Did you know that you could buy a home in Harrisonburg with just $2,000? It’s true, and as we share the cost breakdown I mentioned earlier, you’ll quickly see how. Let’s dive right in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The upfront (or out-of-pocket) expenses include your earnest money deposit, appraisal fees, and inspection fees.&lt;/strong&gt; Inspection and appraisal fees will each cost about $500, while earnest money deposits in Harrisonburg are typically 1% of the purchase price (or at least $1,000). This brings your total out-of-pocket expenses to $2,000. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buying a home can be much more affordable than some people think.%20http://localhost:4000/buying-a-home-doesnt-have-to-break-the-bank.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buying a home can be much more affordable than some people think.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then there’s the matter of your cash to close, which will consist of your down payment and closing costs.&lt;/strong&gt; Your down payment will vary depending on the loan product you use, but some options allow you to purchase a property with 100% financing. In other words, you might not have to put any money down at all. Closing costs will also vary, depending on the lender you work with, but will most often range between 2.5% and 3% of the purchase price. In some cases, though, you can negotiate to have the seller pay them for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;strong&gt;hypothetically, a buyer whose out-of-pocket expenses are $2,000 could get a loan with 100% financing and could have the seller pay their closing costs.&lt;/strong&gt; This means your entire home purchase could run you $2,000 out of pocket. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that buying a home can be much more affordable than some people think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 09:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buying-a-home-doesnt-have-to-break-the-bank.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buying-a-home-doesnt-have-to-break-the-bank.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Make Your Home More Energy Efficient</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_i6Kj4WUCvA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your energy bills are higher than you would like, follow these four tips to make your home more energy efficient today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy-efficient homes are en vogue right now, and for good reason. Not only are they more environmentally friendly, but they also help homeowners save a lot of money on their energy bills each month. Best of all, you can make your home more energy efficient with just a few simple changes. Here are four simple tips you can start with: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Switch to LED lightbulbs.&lt;/strong&gt; Even switching five of the most-used bulbs in your home to LED, you could save an estimated $75 per year off of your electricity bill. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 2. Seal up air leaks.&lt;/strong&gt; When air escapes from the small cracks around your doors and windows, your home’s HVAC unit will have to work overtime to keep the temperature consistent. Simply adding draft guards around doors and caulking around windows and chimneys can make a massive difference. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Not only are energy-efficient homes more environmentally friendly, but they also help homeowners save a lot of money on their energy bills each month.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-make-your-home-more-energy-efficient.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Not only are energy-efficient homes more environmentally friendly, but they also help homeowners save a lot of money on their energy bills each month.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Heat and cool your house efficiently.&lt;/strong&gt; Installing a programmable thermostat is one of the best ways to do so. These allow you to monitor and control your home’s heating and cooling more closely. They even let you control your home’s temperature remotely from your phone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Maintain your HVAC system.&lt;/strong&gt; A poorly maintained HVAC system equates to an uncomfortable living space and high energy bills to boot. So always make sure you’re changing your air filters and ordering annual (or bi-annual) check-ups to keep your HVAC in working order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like an energy audit on your home before or after you implement these tips, please reach out to Charles Hendricks of The Gaines Group Architects by phone at (540) 437-0012 or by visiting his company’s website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thegainesgroup.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.thegainesgroup.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 09:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-make-your-home-more-energy-efficient.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-make-your-home-more-energy-efficient.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Continuing our Discussion on Student Housing in Harrisonburg</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qrwSxlstTz0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As I mentioned in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3tVkU7fLB7Q&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;previous video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;__notset__&quot;&gt;,&lt;/a&gt; buying student housing in Harrisonburg is a tricky, yet worthwhile, pursuit. And, thankfully, there are options that allow you to do so. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Before you decide to invest in student housing, though, realize that &lt;strong&gt;going under-rented for a consecutive year can be majorly detrimental to your cash flow and may jeopardize your investment.&lt;/strong&gt; Most student housing is corporate-owned, so individuals looking to invest in this type of property will be up against some stiff competition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only a select few communities in which individual investors can purchase student housing, including Hunters Ridge, Bradley Drive Camden Townhomes, Pheasant Run, Fox Hills, and Campus View Condos. &lt;strong&gt;The properties in these communities fall under the umbrella of “traditional” student housing.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you are thinking about buying student housing in Harrisonburg, you need to talk to someone who understands the nuances and regulations associated with doing so.%20http://localhost:4000/continuing-our-discussion-on-student-housing-in-harrisonburg.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you are thinking about buying student housing in Harrisonburg, you need to talk to someone who understands the nuances and regulations associated with doing so.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These aren’t your only options, though. You may also want to consider buying property in some non-traditional student neighborhoods, which essentially just means buying a townhome or condo in a regular residential neighborhood and then renting it out to students. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;However, if you choose to pursue this option, &lt;strong&gt;make sure that you are operating within city zoning restrictions as well as the CC&amp;amp;Rs for a specific neighborhood.&lt;/strong&gt; In most residential neighborhoods, only two people who aren’t relatives can live together—a rule specifically designed to keep students from moving outside of student housing neighborhoods. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don’t be fooled into thinking this rule can be easily bypassed. There is a lot of animosity among residents near JMU, where student housing and regular residential housing are somewhat intermingled. The last thing you want to do is break a neighborhood’s restrictions and have to kick people out of their leases. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;The bottom line is that if you are thinking about buying student housing in Harrisonburg, you need to talk to someone who understands the nuances and regulations associated with doing so. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;As it happens, &lt;strong&gt;I started my career by working with student housing.&lt;/strong&gt; I got my feet wet in the real estate industry at a property management company, which opened the door for me to sell nine condos in Hunters Ridge in my first year as an agent. Beyond that, I happen to be a JMU alumnus, so I’m very much in-the-know about where students prefer to live in our area. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, I’m here to help and happy to catch; so please give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/continuing-our-discussion-on-student-housing-in-harrisonburg.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/continuing-our-discussion-on-student-housing-in-harrisonburg.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Buying Student Housing in Harrisonburg</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3tVkU7fLB7Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a lot of calls from people looking to buy investment property in Harrisonburg near JMU to rent to students. Whether you’re a first-time investor, experienced investor, curious JMU student or alum, or JMU parent looking at buying instead of renting, these tips are for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest upside with this kind of investment is cash flow: Student housing typically cash flows very well on a monthly basis because you can rent by the bedroom. &lt;strong&gt;With student housing rents ranging on average from $450 to $600 per bedroom, you could see gross rents around $25,000 for the year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I recommend hiring a property manager.%20http://localhost:4000/what-you-need-to-know-about-buying-student-housing-in-harrisonburg.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I recommend hiring a property manager.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest downside is maintenance. &lt;strong&gt;Students are typically very rough on rental properties, so your turnover costs can be a lot higher. &lt;/strong&gt;It’s possible to mitigate risk by collecting higher security deposits, cleaning fees, etc., but know that if they really tear the place up, it’s a pain to collect back on it. I typically tell people to count on at least a full month’s rent as a maintenance reserve for the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I really recommend hiring a property manager.&lt;/strong&gt; The headaches of dealing with potentially four different tenants with four different sets of parents or guarantors, joint leases vs. separate leases, and knowing when leasing season is at its prime are all nuances that you want a professional to handle. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for part two with more Harrisonburg-specific considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-you-need-to-know-about-buying-student-housing-in-harrisonburg.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-you-need-to-know-about-buying-student-housing-in-harrisonburg.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
