<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Harrisonburg Real Estate Video Blog with Brad Cohen</title>
    <description>Our mission at Harman Realty is to be your best resource for Harrisonburg real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Harman Realty, your professional Harrisonburg Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 12:58:48 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 12:58:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Prepare for the Spring Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tm9nblQFA3A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are my best tips for home sellers who are preparing for the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are my best tips for home sellers who are preparing for the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the time of year when home sellers start asking me how to get their properties ready for the market. We’re in a weird climate right now. The typical curb-appeal tips like sprucing up the yard and updating your landscaping are always going to be in play, but when it comes to making home improvements, you may not have to do a whole lot of updating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I can tailor advice based on your specific situation in the market, but here are a few things I always recommend sellers do in the spring market:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Add a fresh coat of paint. Use a trendy, neutral color that’s attractive to buyers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Update your curb appeal. In my experience, fresh mulch really goes a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. Make the little $100 (and under) fixes. Simple, inexpensive projects like updating a faucet, tacking up some decor, or replacing your backsplash can really make a property shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The big-ticket upgrades aren’t necessary in this market.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-prepare-for-the-spring-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The big-ticket upgrades aren’t necessary in this market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re preparing for the spring market, being aware of current conditions is always the most important thing. If you’re thinking about prepping your home for the spring market, I’d love to give you some specific tips for your specific situation. Just give me a call or send me an email today. I’d be happy to answer any questions you might have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaser: Spring is here, and homeowners have started reaching out to us. Most of them want to know what they should be doing to prepare their homes for the market. We’re in a unique market where you don’t really need to make the big-ticket upgrades to get a high sale price. For example, adding a fresh coat of paint will attract more buyers without costing an arm and a leg. To get my top tips for preparing your home for sale this spring, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-prepare-for-the-spring-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-prepare-for-the-spring-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Still Buy a Home Now</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iTmkW2Q312Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent poll from Fannie Mae showed that only 25% of respondents felt that it was a good time to buy a home. The highest demographic that responded negatively was those aged 18 to 34—only 15% of them felt it was a good time to buy. We all know that interest rates and prices have been increasing for the last two years, so is it still a good time to buy a home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s acknowledge a simple truth: It’s frustrating to be a buyer right now. I feel for everyone who’s had to hear that their offer hasn’t been accepted, whether they’ve heard it once or five times. The lower end of the market has been squeezed the most by price and interest rate escalation, and they also face the most competition. However, &lt;strong&gt;it’s still a great time to buy a house,&lt;/strong&gt; despite the current market conditions, and here are three reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Rates are still very low.&lt;/strong&gt; Though they’re not in the low 3% range we’ve become accustomed to over the last year, they’re still below the historic rates of 5% and 6%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Experts are optimistic about price appreciation.&lt;/strong&gt; In the fourth quarter of 2021, experts predicted an average of 43% appreciation between now and 2026. I think that number may be a bit aggressive, but even the more pessimistic experts were predicting between 22% and 23% appreciation in that same time frame, which is in line with historic averages. So prices will continue to rise, and it will likely be more expensive to buy if you wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Let’s acknowledge a simple truth: It’s frustrating to be a buyer right now.%20http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-its-an-excellent-time-to-buy.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Let’s acknowledge a simple truth: It’s frustrating to be a buyer right now.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Renting is more expensive than owning.&lt;/strong&gt; Rents in our area have continued to climb at a much more dramatic rate than home purchasing affordability. Yes, home prices and rates have been ticking up, and that affects affordability, but if you look at Harrisonburg and Rockingham counties, most of the time, the cost to rent is much higher compared to the payment to purchase the same house. As our real estate market continues to change, those costs will be passed on to tenants more than they’ll affect homeowners. Remember that a mortgage payment puts equity back into your pocket and is a form of a forced savings plan. Paying rent is just paying your landlord’s mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’ll probably be frustrating to buy a home in our present market, the long-term benefits will be completely worth it. Don’t believe every headline you read; always look to your local professionals to help you navigate the market, especially when it’s a tough market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about buying in today’s market or real estate in general, always feel free to reach out to me via text or email. I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-its-an-excellent-time-to-buy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-its-an-excellent-time-to-buy.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Top 3 Predictions for the 2022 Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-u9236QB9rM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our real estate market is off to a fast start despite snowy weather. So far this year, we’ve already had 56 contracts signed, 72 homes sold, and 52 new active listings. Obviously, the snowy weather has not deterred buyers. Here are some of my top predictions and things to watch for the 2022 real estate market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last two years, we’ve seen home prices rise by 20%. &lt;strong&gt;In 2022, I predict that prices will continue to increase but at a much slower rate&lt;/strong&gt; and more in line with historical averages of 4% to 6%. What has happened over the past two years, where we have seen about a 20% increase in prices, is not sustainable. I could spend a lot of time explaining why that happened, but that’s for another video. For 2022, expect that we should see a more “normal” rate of appreciation. And no, I do not expect prices to come down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Interest rates have already started to rise.%20http://localhost:4000/my-top-3-predictions-for-the-2022-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Interest rates have already started to rise.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inventory levels have been extremely low the last few years. &lt;strong&gt;In 2022, I predict that Inventory will increase a little bit, but not so much that I expect a drop in prices.&lt;/strong&gt; New construction has increased but is facing global supply chain challenges in the wake of COVID. Unfortunately, the pace of new construction hasn’t kept up with demand thus far. My hope is that we will see more investors selling rental properties and more empty nesters selling their homes and downsizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, I predict that interest rates will rise in 2022.&lt;/strong&gt; They have already started to. The question is how much. It is no secret that inflation is here and affecting all areas of the economy. The Federal Reserve has already accelerated the tapering of its bond-buying program, and experts are predicting three or four rate hikes this year alone. If you’re planning to buy this year, don’t wait. As interest rates rise, so does your monthly payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about my predictions, current market conditions, or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/my-top-3-predictions-for-the-2022-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/my-top-3-predictions-for-the-2022-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I’m Here for You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9MjuYybpXc4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s message is simple: I’m here for you during these challenging times. Whether you need real estate advice, financial advice, personal advice, or just a quick favor, my entire network is at your disposal. Times are hard, but we’ll get through this together. To see my full message, watch this short video. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 09:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/im-here-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/im-here-for-you.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Never Before Have We Seen This Type of Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qSr-iyx9cYY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Our market is unprecedented right now, and it&amp;rsquo;s a great time to buy or sell.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’re experiencing in our market is unprecedented. Never before have we had such a strong seller’s market while simultaneously experiencing such good buying conditions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of the recording of this video, we have 34 active listings in Harrisonburg and 173 in Rockingham County. We’ve talked a lot about declining inventory the past two years or so, so it’s time to put this into a historical context. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With just 34 active listings, based on last year’s annual pace of sales, if there was no new inventory introduced to the market, we’d sell out in the &lt;em&gt;next month&lt;/em&gt;. Rockingham County isn’t much different—they only have a two-month supply of homes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of unprecedented, let’s talk about rates. Last week, the rate for a 30-year fixed-rate mortgage dropped down to 3%. The last time we even got close to this mark was in 2016, and back then we didn’t have the extreme disparity between buyers and sellers that we do now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Never before have we had such a strong seller’s market while simultaneously experiencing such good buying conditions.%20http://localhost:4000/never-before-have-we-seen-this-type-of-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Never before have we had such a strong seller’s market while simultaneously experiencing such good buying conditions.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When rates drop, affordability increases for most buyers, which creates a surge of buyer activity. If you’re a buyer, this means you’ll face more competition—especially with dwindling inventory. If you’re a seller, you’ll likely see a surge in showing activity and get offers quickly. &lt;strong&gt;With inventory dwindling to what I consider a dangerous level and buyer activity surging, now is the time to sell.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers may be frustrated with the lack of supply, but there will be more, and knowing that rates are as low as they’ve ever been, &lt;strong&gt;it’s also a good time to buy.&lt;/strong&gt; As prices rise and rates go down, affordability generally stays the same. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These conditions make it even more important to work with an agent who has their finger on the pulse of the market and has all the latest information. It may result in you being the one winning out in a bidding war, or generating a bidding war for your home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about our Harrisonburg market or need help buying or selling, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 12:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/never-before-have-we-seen-this-type-of-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/never-before-have-we-seen-this-type-of-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Essential Info for Harrisonburg Homebuyers and Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8xFDa-Px2jI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a look at the latest numbers, and I have important advice to share with homebuyers and sellers in the Harrisonburg area. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know about the 2020 market.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we know it, the spring market will be upon us. If you are thinking about buying or selling in 2020, now is the time for us to get together to plan for it, and here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For home sellers, being early to market is going to give you a win this spring.&lt;/strong&gt; We do not need to be waiting until late March or April to get your house on the market. That may end up backfiring. There has been a major uptick in new housing starts, and competition for sellers this spring and summer may be stronger than what we have seen all of last year. Right now is the time for us to meet, get eyes on your property, and talk about any preparations it needs before putting it on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to do a small bathroom renovation or get a fresh coat of paint put on before selling, now is the time to be making those arrangements before contractors get too busy. I can provide you with quality insights on what to do to get maximum ROI once I get eyes on your property. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, your house does not need to be in “show-ready” condition for me to come look at it the first time. I promise I won’t judge you — nobody lives in a home the way it looks on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s never too early to get your financing in order.%20http://localhost:4000/essential-info-for-harrisonburg-homebuyers-and-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s never too early to get your financing in order.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For buyers, I know it seems rough right now and like there is nothing on the market. That’s normal for this time of year. &lt;strong&gt;Get ready, though, because that is going to change fast&lt;/strong&gt;. Now is the time for us to be meeting to plan your process if you are thinking about buying in 2020. Getting together allows us to plan out your timeline and make sure financing is in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timelines are also important.&lt;/strong&gt; If your lease is up in June, we want to make sure we are actively looking by April to allow enough time to close (30 to 60 days). It’s never too early to start getting financing in order either so you are ready to make an offer when the perfect home hits the market (which could be tomorrow).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get your taxes done. That refund could be a great jumpstart to your down payment or closing costs. By the way, rates are still historically low. Despite prices being up, affordability has not changed dramatically. &lt;strong&gt;Now is the time for us to be meeting to plan out your process.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is, no matter whether you’re buying or selling, let’s get together now and start talking about a plan for the fast-approaching spring market. Call/text/email me or hit me up in the comments. I’m here to help. Also, please send this message onward to someone you know who needs to hear it! I love seeing my videos get shared!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 10:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/essential-info-for-harrisonburg-homebuyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/essential-info-for-harrisonburg-homebuyers-and-sellers.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Smaller Homes Are Becoming More Popular</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RhZ5EP2iQqo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Why are smaller homes becoming more and more popular? Find out today.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, we’ve noticed that smaller homes are becoming increasingly popular among homebuyers. Why is that, though?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand this trend, first &lt;strong&gt;look to the younger generations of buyers, meaning Gen Z and millennials.&lt;/strong&gt; These age groups are trending toward more urban, higher-density homes that provide greater access to amenities. Due to this, we’ve noticed a rise in planned communities with a lot of mixed-use (i.e., residential and commercial) spaces in the same area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Older generations are looking for smaller, lower-maintenance properties as well. They’re looking for increased accessibility in their homes, ideally with fewer stairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=People are trending away from larger homes to spare themselves the effort of cleaning and maintaining all that square footage.%20http://localhost:4000/smaller-homes-are-becoming-more-popular.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“People are trending away from larger homes to spare themselves the effort of cleaning and maintaining all that square footage.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two demographics are the largest segments of the market, which is likely why you’re seeing new construction home size trending downward. In 2019, only 20% of the homes we sold in total were 2,500 square feet or greater, and 93% of new construction homes were below that size threshold. &lt;strong&gt;The largest percentage of the market is looking for homes between 1,500 and 2,500 square feet.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, I think that people are trending away from larger homes to spare themselves the effort of cleaning and maintaining all that square footage. Smaller homes prevent them from becoming house-poor and allow them to invest some of their money into experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I expect to see this trend continue in our market as we advance into the new decade.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have any questions about this trend or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 09:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/smaller-homes-are-becoming-more-popular.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/smaller-homes-are-becoming-more-popular.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Predictions for the 2020 Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BsxwIf8I1KI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m sharing what respected authorities like the National Association of Realtors and the Mortgage Bankers Association are predicting for 2020.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the tail of an interesting 2019, I’m going to give a forecast for the real estate market in 2020. Here’s what experts are predicting: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mortgage interest rates are expected to remain low.&lt;/strong&gt; Experts from Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, NAR, and the Mortgage Bankers Association are predicting that rates should remain fairly stable throughout 2020—great news for buyers looking to capitalize on the lowest rates we’ve seen in history (all under 4%). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite dwindling inventory, three of the four experts I just mentioned are predicting an increase in sales. Thanks to those low rates, buyer demand is still high, and with the uptick of new construction in our area, we expect to see more sales. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I’m very optimistic about this year.%20http://localhost:4000/4-predictions-for-the-2020-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I’m very optimistic about this year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six of the expert entities that keep track of home prices are all predicting an increase in prices throughout 2020—quite in line with what we saw in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A recession isn’t likely, and if it does occur here, it won’t be severe.&lt;/strong&gt; Last year, the number of forecasters predicting a 2020 recession was significant, but more recently, it has gone down quite a bit. No one knows for certain what will happen, but the experts do agree that, should a recession happen this year, its effect on the real estate market will be minimal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very optimistic about this year. I’ve got a lot on my queue and more people are reaching out to me every day. You may recall that I recently sent out a survey. 14% of respondents said they will buy or sell a house in 2020, while 42% said they plan to do a remodel this year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need any recommendations for contractors or builders, or have any questions about the market, feel free to call or email me. I’d be happy to help any way I can. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 09:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-predictions-for-the-2020-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-predictions-for-the-2020-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Should You Break the “Five-Year Rule” of Homeownership?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CH9nTO4ra5I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Generally, homeowners shouldn&amp;rsquo;t sell for at least five years. However, here are three exceptions to that rule.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own your home, or have ever thought about buying one, it’s important to know about the “five-year rule.” Essentially, it’s a widely-accepted concept that you shouldn’t sell your home until you’ve owned it for at least five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, if you sell a home within five years of buying it, you probably won’t recoup the costs from that sale. You may even end up having to bring money to the table. However, there are three notable exceptions to this rule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The property values in your neighborhood start to skyrocket.&lt;/strong&gt; If you can time the market really well or if there’s a crazy demand for homes in your neighborhood, then that’s the time to sell. This is exactly why I’m selling my home right now. I only bought it two years ago, but the neighborhood has been built out since and I’m already sitting on a lot of equity. I should be able to walk away from the sale and put a good amount of the profit I make into my renovation project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Not everything that you dislike about your home can be fixed with renovations.%20http://localhost:4000/when-should-you-break-the-five-year-rule-of-homeownership.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Not everything that you dislike about your home can be fixed with renovations.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The property values in your neighborhood start to plummet.&lt;/strong&gt; We aren’t really seeing this in our market right now, but it’s something you should be aware of. If prices start to drop dramatically in your neighborhood, it might be a good idea to sell now before prices get so low that you can’t sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You have a change in your lifestyle or mentality.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’ve gone through a job relocation, divorce, or you’re simply unhappy with the space, it’s not worth compromising your happiness to stay in the house. While many things that you dislike about your house can be fixed with renovations, not everything can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what certain renovations might cost or if you’re curious about what you can sell your home for right now, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 13:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/when-should-you-break-the-five-year-rule-of-homeownership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/when-should-you-break-the-five-year-rule-of-homeownership.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buying a Home Doesn’t Have to Break the Bank</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zqdQgAjfp44?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much does a Harrisonburg home really cost? Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people are unclear about what it really costs to buy a home. Fortunately, the total expenses of this purchase can be broken down into two categories: upfront expenses and cash to close, both of which we’ll break down for you today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we do that, though, let me share an interesting fact: Did you know that you could buy a home in Harrisonburg with just $2,000? It’s true, and as we share the cost breakdown I mentioned earlier, you’ll quickly see how. Let’s dive right in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The upfront (or out-of-pocket) expenses include your earnest money deposit, appraisal fees, and inspection fees.&lt;/strong&gt; Inspection and appraisal fees will each cost about $500, while earnest money deposits in Harrisonburg are typically 1% of the purchase price (or at least $1,000). This brings your total out-of-pocket expenses to $2,000. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buying a home can be much more affordable than some people think.%20http://localhost:4000/buying-a-home-doesnt-have-to-break-the-bank.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buying a home can be much more affordable than some people think.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then there’s the matter of your cash to close, which will consist of your down payment and closing costs.&lt;/strong&gt; Your down payment will vary depending on the loan product you use, but some options allow you to purchase a property with 100% financing. In other words, you might not have to put any money down at all. Closing costs will also vary, depending on the lender you work with, but will most often range between 2.5% and 3% of the purchase price. In some cases, though, you can negotiate to have the seller pay them for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;strong&gt;hypothetically, a buyer whose out-of-pocket expenses are $2,000 could get a loan with 100% financing and could have the seller pay their closing costs.&lt;/strong&gt; This means your entire home purchase could run you $2,000 out of pocket. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that buying a home can be much more affordable than some people think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 09:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buying-a-home-doesnt-have-to-break-the-bank.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buying-a-home-doesnt-have-to-break-the-bank.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
