<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Harrisonburg Real Estate Podcast with Brad Cohen</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Harman Realty - your professional Harrisonburg Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Brad Cohen</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2022-03-22 12:58:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Brad Cohen</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>brad@bradcohenhomes.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Brad Cohen</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Harrisonburg Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Harman Realty - your professional Harrisonburg Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Prepare for the Spring Real Estate Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-prepare-for-the-spring-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2022-03-16 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Here are my best tips for home sellers who are preparing for the market.
Here are my best tips for home sellers who are preparing for the market.

This is the time of year when home sellers start asking me how to get their properties ready for the market. We’re in a weird climate right now. The typical curb-appeal tips like sprucing up the yard and updating your landscaping are always going to be in play, but when it comes to making home improvements, you may not have to do a whole lot of updating.

I can tailor advice based on your specific situation in the market, but here are a few things I always recommend sellers do in the spring market:

1. Add a fresh coat of paint. Use a trendy, neutral color that’s attractive to buyers

2. Update your curb appeal. In my experience, fresh mulch really goes a long way.

3. Make the little $100 (and under) fixes. Simple, inexpensive projects like updating a faucet, tacking up some decor, or replacing your backsplash can really make a property shine.

“The big-ticket upgrades aren’t necessary in this market.”

When you’re preparing for the spring market, being aware of current conditions is always the most important thing. If you’re thinking about prepping your home for the spring market, I’d love to give you some specific tips for your specific situation. Just give me a call or send me an email today. I’d be happy to answer any questions you might have.

Teaser: Spring is here, and homeowners have started reaching out to us. Most of them want to know what they should be doing to prepare their homes for the market. We’re in a unique market where you don’t really need to make the big-ticket upgrades to get a high sale price. For example, adding a fresh coat of paint will attract more buyers without costing an arm and a leg. To get my top tips for preparing your home for sale this spring, watch this short video.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are my best tips for home sellers who are preparing for the market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are my best tips for home sellers who are preparing for the market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Still Buy a Home Now</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-its-an-excellent-time-to-buy.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2022-02-20 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Why+You+Should+Still+Buy+a+Home+Now.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A recent poll from Fannie Mae showed that only 25% of respondents felt that it was a good time to buy a home. The highest demographic that responded negatively was those aged 18 to 34—only 15% of them felt it was a good time to buy. We all know that interest rates and prices have been increasing for the last two years, so is it still a good time to buy a home?

First, let’s acknowledge a simple truth: It’s frustrating to be a buyer right now. I feel for everyone who’s had to hear that their offer hasn’t been accepted, whether they’ve heard it once or five times. The lower end of the market has been squeezed the most by price and interest rate escalation, and they also face the most competition. However, it’s still a great time to buy a house, despite the current market conditions, and here are three reasons why:

1. Rates are still very low. Though they’re not in the low 3% range we’ve become accustomed to over the last year, they’re still below the historic rates of 5% and 6%.

2. Experts are optimistic about price appreciation. In the fourth quarter of 2021, experts predicted an average of 43% appreciation between now and 2026. I think that number may be a bit aggressive, but even the more pessimistic experts were predicting between 22% and 23% appreciation in that same time frame, which is in line with historic averages. So prices will continue to rise, and it will likely be more expensive to buy if you wait.

“Let’s acknowledge a simple truth: It’s frustrating to be a buyer right now.”

3. Renting is more expensive than owning. Rents in our area have continued to climb at a much more dramatic rate than home purchasing affordability. Yes, home prices and rates have been ticking up, and that affects affordability, but if you look at Harrisonburg and Rockingham counties, most of the time, the cost to rent is much higher compared to the payment to purchase the same house. As our real estate market continues to change, those costs will be passed on to tenants more than they’ll affect homeowners. Remember that a mortgage payment puts equity back into your pocket and is a form of a forced savings plan. Paying rent is just paying your landlord’s mortgage.

While it’ll probably be frustrating to buy a home in our present market, the long-term benefits will be completely worth it. Don’t believe every headline you read; always look to your local professionals to help you navigate the market, especially when it’s a tough market.

If you have any questions about buying in today’s market or real estate in general, always feel free to reach out to me via text or email. I would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Why+You+Should+Still+Buy+a+Home+Now.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Why+You+Should+Still+Buy+a+Home+Now.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Despite ongoing market conditions, it’s still a good time to buy a home</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Despite ongoing market conditions, it’s still a good time to buy a home</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>My Top 3 Predictions for the 2022 Real Estate Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/my-top-3-predictions-for-the-2022-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2022-01-31 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/My+Top+3+Predictions+for+the+2022+Real+Estate+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our real estate market is off to a fast start despite snowy weather. So far this year, we’ve already had 56 contracts signed, 72 homes sold, and 52 new active listings. Obviously, the snowy weather has not deterred buyers. Here are some of my top predictions and things to watch for the 2022 real estate market.

Over the last two years, we’ve seen home prices rise by 20%. In 2022, I predict that prices will continue to increase but at a much slower rate and more in line with historical averages of 4% to 6%. What has happened over the past two years, where we have seen about a 20% increase in prices, is not sustainable. I could spend a lot of time explaining why that happened, but that’s for another video. For 2022, expect that we should see a more “normal” rate of appreciation. And no, I do not expect prices to come down.

“Interest rates have already started to rise.”

Inventory levels have been extremely low the last few years. In 2022, I predict that Inventory will increase a little bit, but not so much that I expect a drop in prices. New construction has increased but is facing global supply chain challenges in the wake of COVID. Unfortunately, the pace of new construction hasn’t kept up with demand thus far. My hope is that we will see more investors selling rental properties and more empty nesters selling their homes and downsizing.

Finally, I predict that interest rates will rise in 2022. They have already started to. The question is how much. It is no secret that inflation is here and affecting all areas of the economy. The Federal Reserve has already accelerated the tapering of its bond-buying program, and experts are predicting three or four rate hikes this year alone. If you’re planning to buy this year, don’t wait. As interest rates rise, so does your monthly payment.

If you have any questions for me about my predictions, current market conditions, or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/My+Top+3+Predictions+for+the+2022+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/My+Top+3+Predictions+for+the+2022+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are my top three predictions for our real estate market in 2022.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are my top three predictions for our real estate market in 2022.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>I’m Here for You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/im-here-for-you.html</link>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2020-03-26 09:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today’s message is simple: I’m here for you during these challenging times. Whether you need real estate advice, financial advice, personal advice, or just a quick favor, my entire network is at your disposal. Times are hard, but we’ll get through this together. To see my full message, watch this short video. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Never Before Have We Seen This Type of Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/never-before-have-we-seen-this-type-of-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2020-03-09 12:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Our market is unprecedented right now, and it&rsquo;s a great time to buy or sell.&nbsp;

 

What we’re experiencing in our market is unprecedented. Never before have we had such a strong seller’s market while simultaneously experiencing such good buying conditions. 

As of the recording of this video, we have 34 active listings in Harrisonburg and 173 in Rockingham County. We’ve talked a lot about declining inventory the past two years or so, so it’s time to put this into a historical context. 

With just 34 active listings, based on last year’s annual pace of sales, if there was no new inventory introduced to the market, we’d sell out in the next month. Rockingham County isn’t much different—they only have a two-month supply of homes. 

Speaking of unprecedented, let’s talk about rates. Last week, the rate for a 30-year fixed-rate mortgage dropped down to 3%. The last time we even got close to this mark was in 2016, and back then we didn’t have the extreme disparity between buyers and sellers that we do now. 

“Never before have we had such a strong seller’s market while simultaneously experiencing such good buying conditions.”

When rates drop, affordability increases for most buyers, which creates a surge of buyer activity. If you’re a buyer, this means you’ll face more competition—especially with dwindling inventory. If you’re a seller, you’ll likely see a surge in showing activity and get offers quickly. With inventory dwindling to what I consider a dangerous level and buyer activity surging, now is the time to sell. 

Buyers may be frustrated with the lack of supply, but there will be more, and knowing that rates are as low as they’ve ever been, it’s also a good time to buy. As prices rise and rates go down, affordability generally stays the same. 

These conditions make it even more important to work with an agent who has their finger on the pulse of the market and has all the latest information. It may result in you being the one winning out in a bidding war, or generating a bidding war for your home. 

If you have questions about our Harrisonburg market or need help buying or selling, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our market is unprecedented right now, and it’s a great time to buy or sell.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our market is unprecedented right now, and it’s a great time to buy or sell.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Essential Info for Harrisonburg Homebuyers and Sellers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/essential-info-for-harrisonburg-homebuyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-13 10:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I&rsquo;ve taken a look at the latest numbers, and I have important advice to share with homebuyers and sellers in the Harrisonburg area. Here&rsquo;s what you need to know about the 2020 market.

 

Before we know it, the spring market will be upon us. If you are thinking about buying or selling in 2020, now is the time for us to get together to plan for it, and here’s why:

For home sellers, being early to market is going to give you a win this spring. We do not need to be waiting until late March or April to get your house on the market. That may end up backfiring. There has been a major uptick in new housing starts, and competition for sellers this spring and summer may be stronger than what we have seen all of last year. Right now is the time for us to meet, get eyes on your property, and talk about any preparations it needs before putting it on the market.

If you want to do a small bathroom renovation or get a fresh coat of paint put on before selling, now is the time to be making those arrangements before contractors get too busy. I can provide you with quality insights on what to do to get maximum ROI once I get eyes on your property. 

By the way, your house does not need to be in “show-ready” condition for me to come look at it the first time. I promise I won’t judge you — nobody lives in a home the way it looks on the market.

“It’s never too early to get your financing in order.”

For buyers, I know it seems rough right now and like there is nothing on the market. That’s normal for this time of year. Get ready, though, because that is going to change fast. Now is the time for us to be meeting to plan your process if you are thinking about buying in 2020. Getting together allows us to plan out your timeline and make sure financing is in order.

Timelines are also important. If your lease is up in June, we want to make sure we are actively looking by April to allow enough time to close (30 to 60 days). It’s never too early to start getting financing in order either so you are ready to make an offer when the perfect home hits the market (which could be tomorrow).

Get your taxes done. That refund could be a great jumpstart to your down payment or closing costs. By the way, rates are still historically low. Despite prices being up, affordability has not changed dramatically. Now is the time for us to be meeting to plan out your process.

The bottom line is, no matter whether you’re buying or selling, let’s get together now and start talking about a plan for the fast-approaching spring market. Call/text/email me or hit me up in the comments. I’m here to help. Also, please send this message onward to someone you know who needs to hear it! I love seeing my videos get shared!

We look forward to hearing from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’ve taken a look at the latest numbers, and I have important advice to share with homebuyers and sellers in the Harrisonburg area. Here’s what you need to know about the 2020 market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’ve taken a look at the latest numbers, and I have important advice to share with homebuyers and sellers in the Harrisonburg area. Here’s what you need to know about the 2020 market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Smaller Homes Are Becoming More Popular</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/smaller-homes-are-becoming-more-popular.html</link>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-27 09:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Why are smaller homes becoming more and more popular? Find out today.

 

Over the past few years, we’ve noticed that smaller homes are becoming increasingly popular among homebuyers. Why is that, though?

To understand this trend, first look to the younger generations of buyers, meaning Gen Z and millennials. These age groups are trending toward more urban, higher-density homes that provide greater access to amenities. Due to this, we’ve noticed a rise in planned communities with a lot of mixed-use (i.e., residential and commercial) spaces in the same area.

Older generations are looking for smaller, lower-maintenance properties as well. They’re looking for increased accessibility in their homes, ideally with fewer stairs.

“People are trending away from larger homes to spare themselves the effort of cleaning and maintaining all that square footage.”

These two demographics are the largest segments of the market, which is likely why you’re seeing new construction home size trending downward. In 2019, only 20% of the homes we sold in total were 2,500 square feet or greater, and 93% of new construction homes were below that size threshold. The largest percentage of the market is looking for homes between 1,500 and 2,500 square feet.  

In general, I think that people are trending away from larger homes to spare themselves the effort of cleaning and maintaining all that square footage. Smaller homes prevent them from becoming house-poor and allow them to invest some of their money into experiences.

I expect to see this trend continue in our market as we advance into the new decade. If you have any questions about this trend or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out to us.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Why are smaller homes becoming more and more popular? Find out today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Why are smaller homes becoming more and more popular? Find out today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Predictions for the 2020 Real Estate Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-predictions-for-the-2020-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-13 09:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I&rsquo;m sharing what respected authorities like the National Association of Realtors and the Mortgage Bankers Association are predicting for 2020.

 

On the tail of an interesting 2019, I’m going to give a forecast for the real estate market in 2020. Here’s what experts are predicting: 

Mortgage interest rates are expected to remain low. Experts from Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, NAR, and the Mortgage Bankers Association are predicting that rates should remain fairly stable throughout 2020—great news for buyers looking to capitalize on the lowest rates we’ve seen in history (all under 4%). 

Despite dwindling inventory, three of the four experts I just mentioned are predicting an increase in sales. Thanks to those low rates, buyer demand is still high, and with the uptick of new construction in our area, we expect to see more sales. 

“I’m very optimistic about this year.”

Six of the expert entities that keep track of home prices are all predicting an increase in prices throughout 2020—quite in line with what we saw in 2019. 

A recession isn’t likely, and if it does occur here, it won’t be severe. Last year, the number of forecasters predicting a 2020 recession was significant, but more recently, it has gone down quite a bit. No one knows for certain what will happen, but the experts do agree that, should a recession happen this year, its effect on the real estate market will be minimal. 

I’m very optimistic about this year. I’ve got a lot on my queue and more people are reaching out to me every day. You may recall that I recently sent out a survey. 14% of respondents said they will buy or sell a house in 2020, while 42% said they plan to do a remodel this year. 

If you need any recommendations for contractors or builders, or have any questions about the market, feel free to call or email me. I’d be happy to help any way I can. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m sharing what respected authorities like the National Association or Realtors and the Mortgage Bankers Association are predicting for 2020.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m sharing what respected authorities like the National Association or Realtors and the Mortgage Bankers Association are predicting for 2020.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Should You Break the “Five-Year Rule” of Homeownership?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/when-should-you-break-the-five-year-rule-of-homeownership.html</link>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-25 13:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Generally, homeowners shouldn&rsquo;t sell for at least five years. However, here are three exceptions to that rule.

 

If you own your home, or have ever thought about buying one, it’s important to know about the “five-year rule.” Essentially, it’s a widely-accepted concept that you shouldn’t sell your home until you’ve owned it for at least five years.

Generally speaking, if you sell a home within five years of buying it, you probably won’t recoup the costs from that sale. You may even end up having to bring money to the table. However, there are three notable exceptions to this rule:

1. The property values in your neighborhood start to skyrocket. If you can time the market really well or if there’s a crazy demand for homes in your neighborhood, then that’s the time to sell. This is exactly why I’m selling my home right now. I only bought it two years ago, but the neighborhood has been built out since and I’m already sitting on a lot of equity. I should be able to walk away from the sale and put a good amount of the profit I make into my renovation project.

“Not everything that you dislike about your home can be fixed with renovations.”

2. The property values in your neighborhood start to plummet. We aren’t really seeing this in our market right now, but it’s something you should be aware of. If prices start to drop dramatically in your neighborhood, it might be a good idea to sell now before prices get so low that you can’t sell.

3. You have a change in your lifestyle or mentality. If you’ve gone through a job relocation, divorce, or you’re simply unhappy with the space, it’s not worth compromising your happiness to stay in the house. While many things that you dislike about your house can be fixed with renovations, not everything can.

If you have any questions about what certain renovations might cost or if you’re curious about what you can sell your home for right now, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Generally, homeowners shouldn’t sell for at least five years. However, here are three exceptions to that rule.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Generally, homeowners shouldn’t sell for at least five years. However, here are three exceptions to that rule.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Buying a Home Doesn’t Have to Break the Bank</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buying-a-home-doesnt-have-to-break-the-bank.html</link>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-25 09:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

How much does a Harrisonburg home really cost? Let&rsquo;s discuss.

 

Many people are unclear about what it really costs to buy a home. Fortunately, the total expenses of this purchase can be broken down into two categories: upfront expenses and cash to close, both of which we’ll break down for you today. 

Before we do that, though, let me share an interesting fact: Did you know that you could buy a home in Harrisonburg with just $2,000? It’s true, and as we share the cost breakdown I mentioned earlier, you’ll quickly see how. Let’s dive right in.

The upfront (or out-of-pocket) expenses include your earnest money deposit, appraisal fees, and inspection fees. Inspection and appraisal fees will each cost about $500, while earnest money deposits in Harrisonburg are typically 1% of the purchase price (or at least $1,000). This brings your total out-of-pocket expenses to $2,000. 

“Buying a home can be much more affordable than some people think.”

Then there’s the matter of your cash to close, which will consist of your down payment and closing costs. Your down payment will vary depending on the loan product you use, but some options allow you to purchase a property with 100% financing. In other words, you might not have to put any money down at all. Closing costs will also vary, depending on the lender you work with, but will most often range between 2.5% and 3% of the purchase price. In some cases, though, you can negotiate to have the seller pay them for you. 

So, hypothetically, a buyer whose out-of-pocket expenses are $2,000 could get a loan with 100% financing and could have the seller pay their closing costs. This means your entire home purchase could run you $2,000 out of pocket. 

The bottom line is that buying a home can be much more affordable than some people think.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How much does a Harrisonburg home really cost? Let’s discuss.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How much does a Harrisonburg home really cost? Let’s discuss.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Make Your Home More Energy Efficient</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-make-your-home-more-energy-efficient.html</link>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-11 09:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/How+to+Make+Your+Home+More+Energy+Efficient.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If your energy bills are higher than you would like, follow these four tips to make your home more energy efficient today.

&nbsp;

Energy-efficient homes are en vogue right now, and for good reason. Not only are they more environmentally friendly, but they also help homeowners save a lot of money on their energy bills each month. Best of all, you can make your home more energy efficient with just a few simple changes. Here are four simple tips you can start with: 

1. Switch to LED lightbulbs. Even switching five of the most-used bulbs in your home to LED, you could save an estimated $75 per year off of your electricity bill. 

 2. Seal up air leaks. When air escapes from the small cracks around your doors and windows, your home’s HVAC unit will have to work overtime to keep the temperature consistent. Simply adding draft guards around doors and caulking around windows and chimneys can make a massive difference. 

“Not only are energy-efficient homes more environmentally friendly, but they also help homeowners save a lot of money on their energy bills each month.”

3. Heat and cool your house efficiently. Installing a programmable thermostat is one of the best ways to do so. These allow you to monitor and control your home’s heating and cooling more closely. They even let you control your home’s temperature remotely from your phone. 

4. Maintain your HVAC system. A poorly maintained HVAC system equates to an uncomfortable living space and high energy bills to boot. So always make sure you’re changing your air filters and ordering annual (or bi-annual) check-ups to keep your HVAC in working order.

If you would like an energy audit on your home before or after you implement these tips, please reach out to Charles Hendricks of The Gaines Group Architects by phone at (540) 437-0012 or by visiting his company’s website: www.thegainesgroup.com

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/How+to+Make+Your+Home+More+Energy+Efficient.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/How+to+Make+Your+Home+More+Energy+Efficient.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If your energy bills are higher than you would like, follow these four tips to make your home more energy efficient today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If your energy bills are higher than you would like, follow these four tips to make your home more energy efficient today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Continuing our Discussion on Student Housing in Harrisonburg</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/continuing-our-discussion-on-student-housing-in-harrisonburg.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-26 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Continuing+our+Discussion+on+Student+Housing+in+Harrisonburg.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As I mentioned in my previous video, buying student housing in Harrisonburg is a tricky, yet worthwhile, pursuit. And, thankfully, there are options that allow you to do so.  Before you decide to invest in student housing, though, realize that going under-rented for a consecutive year can be majorly detrimental to your cash flow and may jeopardize your investment. Most student housing is corporate-owned, so individuals looking to invest in this type of property will be up against some stiff competition. 

There are only a select few communities in which individual investors can purchase student housing, including Hunters Ridge, Bradley Drive Camden Townhomes, Pheasant Run, Fox Hills, and Campus View Condos. The properties in these communities fall under the umbrella of “traditional” student housing. 

“If you are thinking about buying student housing in Harrisonburg, you need to talk to someone who understands the nuances and regulations associated with doing so.”

These aren’t your only options, though. You may also want to consider buying property in some non-traditional student neighborhoods, which essentially just means buying a townhome or condo in a regular residential neighborhood and then renting it out to students.  However, if you choose to pursue this option, make sure that you are operating within city zoning restrictions as well as the CC&amp;Rs for a specific neighborhood. In most residential neighborhoods, only two people who aren’t relatives can live together—a rule specifically designed to keep students from moving outside of student housing neighborhoods. 

And don’t be fooled into thinking this rule can be easily bypassed. There is a lot of animosity among residents near JMU, where student housing and regular residential housing are somewhat intermingled. The last thing you want to do is break a neighborhood’s restrictions and have to kick people out of their leases.  The bottom line is that if you are thinking about buying student housing in Harrisonburg, you need to talk to someone who understands the nuances and regulations associated with doing so.  As it happens, I started my career by working with student housing. I got my feet wet in the real estate industry at a property management company, which opened the door for me to sell nine condos in Hunters Ridge in my first year as an agent. Beyond that, I happen to be a JMU alumnus, so I’m very much in-the-know about where students prefer to live in our area.  If you have any other questions or would like more information, I’m here to help and happy to catch; so please give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Continuing+our+Discussion+on+Student+Housing+in+Harrisonburg.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Continuing+our+Discussion+on+Student+Housing+in+Harrisonburg.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re interested in investing in student housing, this message is for you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re interested in investing in student housing, this message is for you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Buying Student Housing in Harrisonburg</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-you-need-to-know-about-buying-student-housing-in-harrisonburg.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-11 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Home+Ownership+as+an+Investment.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I get a lot of calls from people looking to buy investment property in Harrisonburg near JMU to rent to students. Whether you’re a first-time investor, experienced investor, curious JMU student or alum, or JMU parent looking at buying instead of renting, these tips are for you. 

The biggest upside with this kind of investment is cash flow: Student housing typically cash flows very well on a monthly basis because you can rent by the bedroom. With student housing rents ranging on average from $450 to $600 per bedroom, you could see gross rents around $25,000 for the year.

“I recommend hiring a property manager.”

The biggest downside is maintenance. Students are typically very rough on rental properties, so your turnover costs can be a lot higher. It’s possible to mitigate risk by collecting higher security deposits, cleaning fees, etc., but know that if they really tear the place up, it’s a pain to collect back on it. I typically tell people to count on at least a full month’s rent as a maintenance reserve for the year.

I really recommend hiring a property manager. The headaches of dealing with potentially four different tenants with four different sets of parents or guarantors, joint leases vs. separate leases, and knowing when leasing season is at its prime are all nuances that you want a professional to handle. 

Stay tuned for part two with more Harrisonburg-specific considerations.

If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Home+Ownership+as+an+Investment.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Home+Ownership+as+an+Investment.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Thinking about investing in student housing in Harrisonburg? Here’s some information you should have before starting the process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Thinking about investing in student housing in Harrisonburg? Here’s some information you should have before starting the process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Homeownership Still a Good Investment?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-homeownership-still-a-good-investment.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-30 09:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Home+Ownership+as+an+Investment.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re now more than halfway through 2019, and we’re in the heat of the summer market. This time of year is always the busiest for real estate, and there’s still a lot of uncertainty about what’s going on in the Harrisonburg market. Currently, we’re dealing with really tight inventory conditions, which naturally leads to a lot of multiple-offer situations and frustrated buyers. 

On the national and global level, there’s also a lot of uncertainty about the economy and how that will ultimately affect the housing industry. For one, next year is an election year, and many wonder about the political implications. There are questions about how tariffs will affect us domestically and globally, for example. We’re also dealing with an inverted yield curve, which has historically always preceded a recession.

“A recent study from the Federal Reserve Bank showed that 65% of Americans still think that owning real estate is a strong investment.”

A recent study from the Federal Reserve Bank showed that despite all this chatter, 65% of Americans still think that owning real estate is a strong investment. This is a 9% increase since 2014. Here’s why homeownership is still considered such a good investment:

1. Your home is a forced savings plan. By paying your mortgage every month, you’re building equity in your property, which you can then use for other investments like a kitchen remodel or a home equity line of credit. Equity in your home is one of the most accessible forms of cash out there. 

2. The wealthiest 1% either have their hands in real estate or have made their money through real estate. Most everyone ranks real estate as the best investment for the long-term growth of your net worth—even over stocks, bonds, mutual funds, precious metals, and savings accounts.

So in the end, don’t listen to all the hype. Talk to your trusted financial advisors, tax advisors, and real estate agents who already have their fingers on the pulse of the market. They’ll help you to figure out what’s going on before you make any decisions.

If you’re currently renting, reach out to us. Let’s talk about getting you on the path to homeownership.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Home+Ownership+as+an+Investment.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Home+Ownership+as+an+Investment.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, let’s talk about homeownership as an investment. Find out what you need to know right here.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, let’s talk about homeownership as an investment. Find out what you need to know right here.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Caused the Inventory Crisis in Our Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-caused-the-inventory-crisis-in-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-15 12:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Harrisonburg+and+Rockingham+County's+Inventory+Crisis.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our company recently did an event called “Ignite Harrisonburg” where we brought together about 140 community leaders to discuss the issues surrounding housing and development and to get an idea of what people really need. 

After we did some quick surveys and came up with a consensus, we found that the central theme was affordability: 66% of people said we needed more single-family homes in the $150,000 to $300,000 price range. 

What’s caused this affordability crisis? It all boils down to three factors:

1. Resale prices are up. This is largely due to dwindling supply and rising demand amongst buyers. Inventory has been tight in all price ranges and that has made things challenging for buyers.

2. There are similar housing needs across demographics. For the first time, millennials and retirees looking to downsize are searching for the same types of properties—starter homes in the $150,000 to $300,000 price range I mentioned above. That’s where the demand is, and that’s where the two largest demographics in the market are both looking.

“We need large-scale development in the $200,000 to $300,000 price range to meet the needs of the larger home buying demographics.”

3. No new residential properties are being built on a large scale. If you see a lot of dirt being moved right now, it’s for either commercial property or student housing, and there are three reasons why this is: land is expensive, building costs are rising, and government restrictions have made construction expensive and difficult. 

What’s the solution to this crisis? There is no easy answer. We’re dealing with a perfect storm that’s led us to this situation. For one thing, we need large-scale development in the $200,000 to $300,000 price range to meet the needs of the larger home buying demographics, which will hopefully start a chain reaction for the other demographics. 

I would love to hear your thoughts on this topic and what our other needs are in Harrisonburg and Rockingham counties, so please feel free to leave a comment in the comment section below or click on this link and take a quick survey. Let’s solve this crisis together. 

As always, if you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I’d love to hear from you. In the meantime, I look forward to seeing you at the next Ignite Harrisonburg! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Harrisonburg+and+Rockingham+County's+Inventory+Crisis.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Harrisonburg+and+Rockingham+County's+Inventory+Crisis.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There is an inventory crisis in our market, but there may be a solution.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There is an inventory crisis in our market, but there may be a solution.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which Days to List Your Home (and Which Days Not to)</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/which-days-to-list-your-home-and-which-days-not-to.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-25 10:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Brad+Cohen%2C+Realtor-+When+is+the+Best+Day+to+List+Your+Home_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Is there a “best” day to list your property? 

Yes, but first let’s talk about the days you don’t want to put your home on the market: Friday, Saturday, and Sunday. This is when most people are out and about looking for homes, which means their agents are out with them instead of sitting down at their computers checking the MLS for new listings. 

The first 24 hours on the MLS are crucial in terms of exposing your home to the most agents possible. Roughly 87% of all buyers have an agent, so you don’t want to list your home when no one’s looking. 

All agents have property alert systems on their phone, but scheduling showings when you’re out with other clients is very challenging, especially when you’re trying to give the common courtesy of a 24-hour notice. Listing on Saturday or Sunday is acceptable only when you’ve already put a sign in your yard or started a “coming soon” campaign. 

“The first 24 hours on the MLS are crucial in terms of exposing your home to the most agents possible.”

What about Friday? Well, don’t you like to know what you’re doing this weekend before 4 p.m. on Friday afternoon? I sure do, and when we see a home hit the market during that time—when we’re already frantically scheduling showings before our office closes—it becomes very difficult to change plans. 

When I get a call on a weekend about a brand-new listing that’s hit the market, my weekend plans vanish. Whether I’m out showing homes to a client or skydiving (as I often like to do on the weekends), I have no choice but to go see it in these market conditions. Why not make everyone’s lives easier and put your home in front of as many eyes as possible by listing before then?

So when are the best days to list? Preferably Tuesdays or Wednesdays. This gives consumers the most time to see it while it syndicates out to Trulia, Zillow, Realtor.com, etc. This also makes your life more convenient because you can plan to be out of the house once the weekend hits and showings start. 

To be clear, if you’re a buyer, this doesn’t mean you shouldn’t call me on the weekends if you see a new home you like. Please do! 

If you have any questions about this topic or you’re ready to buy or sell a home in Harrisonburg, don’t hesitate to give me a shout. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Brad+Cohen%2C+Realtor-+When+is+the+Best+Day+to+List+Your+Home_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Brad+Cohen%2C+Realtor-+When+is+the+Best+Day+to+List+Your+Home_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re a home seller, some days are better than others to list on—here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re a home seller, some days are better than others to list on—here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Now Is a Great Time to Sell a Townhouse</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-now-is-a-great-time-to-sell-a-townhouse.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-11 14:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Brad+Cohen%2C+Realtor-+Why+Now+Is+a+Great+Time+to+Sell+a+Townhouse+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’ve had 138 attached home sales in our area so far this year, 68 of which were in Harrisonburg. On average, the sellers behind these properties have been earning 99% of their asking price, on average. 

And homes aren’t just selling for high prices right now—they’re also selling quickly. Right now, listings are spending an average of just 35 days on the market. Conditions are so hot that we currently have just 16 attached homes available in Harrisonburg, and only 41 available across Harrisonburg and Rockingham Counties. 

“Whether you bought a townhouse as a starter home or an investment property, now is the time to sell.”

This extremely limited inventory, especially among homes priced at or below $200,000, has caused many buyers to set their sights on townhomes. And for those with a townhome to sell in our area, this is great news. Between this high level of demand and the fact that prices have risen 10% year to date, sellers are in a prime position to sell quickly and for top dollar. 

The bottom line is this: Whether you bought a townhouse as a starter home or an investment property, now is the time to sell.

Of course, it’s also a great time to sell single-family homes. So if you have any other questions or would like more information about how I can help you with your real estate goals, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Brad+Cohen%2C+Realtor-+Why+Now+Is+a+Great+Time+to+Sell+a+Townhouse+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Brad+Cohen/Brad+Cohen%2C+Realtor-+Why+Now+Is+a+Great+Time+to+Sell+a+Townhouse+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’ve got a townhouse you’ve been thinking of selling, it’s time to get off the fence and make a move.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’ve got a townhouse you’ve been thinking of selling, it’s time to get off the fence and make a move.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Inside Look at Harrisonburg’s Jacktown Loft & Discussing Airbnb</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-inside-look-at-harrisonburgs-jacktown-loft-discussing-airbnb.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-12 11:38:09 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+What+to+Know+About+Airbnb+and+Touring+a+Jacktown+Loft.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Anyone who knows me knows that I’m a huge advocate for and frequenter of Jack Brown’s, Billy Jack’s, and The Hideaway. What you may not know is that there’s an apartment space atop all of it called Jacktown Loft, and I’ve been granted the unique privilege to give you a tour of it. While on our tour, we’ll also discuss Airbnb and the benefits of renting out your property.  

Airbnb made some major waves when it entered the scene a few years ago as an alternative to hotels for vacationers. Its purpose has widened beyond just vacation stays and is a popular option for tourists, people traveling on business, etc. It’s opened the door for people who want to stay in a non-hotel setting while away from home. 

Harrisonburg has become a hub for tourism due to our magnificent downtown cuisine scene, and the Jacktown Loft is no exception to this; sitting right above two of the most popular bar-restaurants in the downtown area, it’s become a highly sought-after place for tourists to stay. If this interests you, be sure to contact the owner or check it out on Airbnb. 

“Harrisonburg has become a hub for tourism due to our magnificent downtown cuisine scene, and the Jacktown Loft is no exception to this.”

The Jacktown Loft is a four-bedroom, four-bath space with two queen-sized beds, two twin-sized beds, and a den area complete with a sleeper sofa. 

Before we dive into the tour, let’s briefly talk about the upsides of Airbnb for homeowners. Via Airbnb, a number of my clients have found success in offsetting their mortgage costs by renting portions of their home. Because there’s an “at-home” feeling with these scenarios, there’s certainly a lot of renter demand. 

In fact, two of my clients who’ve used Airbnb in this way have told me that they’re paying their mortgage in full just from the rent they’re generating. In short, it can be greatly beneficial to you as a homeowner to use this strategy. If you have any further questions pertaining to Airbnb, don’t hesitate to contact me. 

In the meantime, let’s get to the tour! Starting at 2:51 in the video, you can see for yourself all that the Jacktown Loft has to offer. 

A big thanks to Aaron Ludwig and the whole Jacktown family for the opportunity to bring you this little preview of the loft. Again, if you have any questions about real estate, Airbnb, or the like, feel free to reach out. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+What+to+Know+About+Airbnb+and+Touring+a+Jacktown+Loft.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+What+to+Know+About+Airbnb+and+Touring+a+Jacktown+Loft.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’ll give you my insights into Airbnb, and I’m especially excited to bring you along for a tour of Jacktown Loft!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’ll give you my insights into Airbnb, and I’m especially excited to bring you along for a tour of Jacktown Loft!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Closings Work And Why They Work Best On Wednesdays</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-closings-work-and-why-they-work-best-on-wednesdays.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-26 13:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+Closings+Work+and+Why+You+Should+Close+on+Wednesdays+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

A home closing signals the end of the transaction, which is an exciting moment for buyers and sellers alike. At this point, appraisals have been finished, inspections have been done, and financing is in order. It’s time to close—but what does closing entail? And why should you wait until Wednesday to close?

At closing, the buyers, sellers, Realtors, representative or attorney, and lender will all meet. In some cases, people will sign documents at different times throughout the day—the seller comes by in the morning and the buyer comes later, for example. 

Sellers typically have fewer documents to sign; the buyer has to resign all of their loan documents, sign a number of disclosures, and more. The closing documents are then reviewed by both sides so that everything looks correct.

“If you set the closing date for Wednesday, you have a buffer of two business days on either side.”

After this, the attorney takes the documents to the clerk’s office and has the deed recorded, which ends the closing. Keys are exchanged at the closing table, and this is a great time for the buyer to ask the seller any final questions they have. 

Though people often want to close at arbitrary times to save on things like proration, I think it’s a much better option to simply shoot for Wednesdays. I had a client who wanted to close on Friday in order to start moving on Saturday, but here’s the problem—what if there’s a delay? 

The closing is an “on or about” date for both parties, so if you don’t close on that set date, the closing could shift to a few days before or after it. It’s done this way to avoid a pile of extra paperwork.

If you set the closing date for Wednesday, you have a buffer of two business days on either side. This gives you time to wrap up any last-minute tasks, and it also gives you the ability to push your closing back a couple of days if needed. Then, you won’t be in fear of missing out on the perfect Saturday moving day!

If you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+Closings+Work+and+Why+You+Should+Close+on+Wednesdays+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+Closings+Work+and+Why+You+Should+Close+on+Wednesdays+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Closing on a home is a huge moment in a homebuyer’s life. Here’s what you need to know about the big day.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Closing on a home is a huge moment in a homebuyer’s life. Here’s what you need to know about the big day.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What to Know If You’re Planning to Buy & Sell Your Home Simultaneously</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-to-know-if-youre-planning-to-buy-sell-your-home-simultaneously.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-11 10:48:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Buying+and+Selling+at+the+Same+Time.mp4</guid>
        <description>

For today’s video, I’m live with Bree for a short Q&amp;A on buying and selling a home at the same time.

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to each question and its respective answer. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:

0:47—Is buying and selling at the same time a common trend in our market?

1:20—What is the difference between a contingent buyer and a non-contingent buyer?

1:57—What are the pros and cons of buying before selling your existing home?

3:29—What are the pros and cons of selling your existing home before buying a new one?

4:37—What are some general tips to prepare for this sort of situation?

5:25—How you can contact me

If you have any questions or comments for me, feel free to send me an email at Brad@BradCohenHomes.com or call me at 540-830-7239. I look forward to hearing from you!

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Buying+and+Selling+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Buying+and+Selling+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What should anyone thinking about buying and selling at the same time know? Find out in my Q&A session with Bree.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What should anyone thinking about buying and selling at the same time know? Find out in my Q&A session with Bree.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Working With a Realtor Outside of Your Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/working-with-a-realtor-outside-of-your-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-25 10:13:44 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+a+Realtor+Who+Is+Outside+Your+Market+Can+Help+You.mp4</guid>
        <description>

 

Real estate is a local business, but I know many of you who receive these videos live outside of the Harrisonburg, Virginia market I work in. That’s why I want to talk about how working with a Realtor outside of your local market can still benefit you, whether you’re buying or selling.

First, it’s a familiar face to have a conversation with. Buying or selling a home is an important life decision, and it’s something you may not want to talk about with a complete stranger. If you’re in the beginning stages of the buying or selling process and you’re just trying to gather some general information, talking with a Realtor outside of your market is a great way to get some unbiased, realistic advice. You’re not in a high-pressure sales environment, so you can have a truly honest conversation.

“Realtors know how to find other quality Realtors.”

Second, you can gain familiarity with the process. Buying and selling a home is different from market to market, but not drastically so. If you need general information of what the process looks like when you’re thinking of doing either, talking to a quality agent in any market is a smart move. When you get down to the nuts and bolts of the upcoming transaction, that’s when you want to talk to a hyperlocal expert.

Third, you’ll make connections with quality Realtors. Realtors know how to find other quality Realtors. When you need to find an agent anywhere in the world, it’s handy to be able to have another agent do some outreach on your behalf. Whether it’s through online reviews, our broker-to-broker network, conferences, or training seminars, I can match you up with someone in your area who will help you get the best deal possible.

So, if you’re thinking of buying or selling a home and you know another Realtor who works in another market, don’t be afraid to give them a call. You’ll know you’re working with a trusted advisor and you’re starting off on the right foot for one of the most important decisions of your life.

If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to give me a call. I’d love to help you.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+a+Realtor+Who+Is+Outside+Your+Market+Can+Help+You.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+a+Realtor+Who+Is+Outside+Your+Market+Can+Help+You.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Working with a Realtor outside of your market during the beginning phases of the buying or selling process is tremendously beneficial. Here’s why that is.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Working with a Realtor outside of your market during the beginning phases of the buying or selling process is tremendously beneficial. Here’s why that is.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Two Factors That Determine a Home’s Appeal</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-two-factors-that-determine-a-homes-appeal.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-08 13:27:53 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+to+Tell+When+a+Listing+Is+Overpriced.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When I talk to both buyers and sellers, there’s no shortage of the question: “How does one know if a listing is overpriced?”

There are two main factors that enter into the equation of a home’s true value: its price and condition. Buyers are looking for value, which is a direct reflection of the price versus the condition of the property.

Sellers thinking about listing their property need to understand that the name of the game is realistic expectations. Have a conversation with your Realtor and walk through your home viewing it through a buyer’s lens, rather than your own.

“Buyers are looking for value, which is a direct reflection of the price versus the condition of the property.”

Think about what a buyer may have misgivings about or object to when assessing the property’s condition, what updates can you make prior to listing that will maximize your ROI, and how you can compensate for what you can’t control.

As it concerns price, get to know the data and analyze the comparables in your area; if homes in your neighborhood are selling in 30 days or less, and your home is past that mark, it’s a direct reflection of the price or condition.    

To ensure that your home isn’t overpriced, reduce the price in accordance with the collective buyer feedback, whether direct or indirect. As for condition, you’ll likely have to put a little more thought, time, and resources into adjustments. The sticking point for buyers could be anything from an obnoxiously painted room that needs repainting to an outdated kitchen or bathroom that could use a remodel.

Two signs, in particular, are all the evidence you need to know your home is overpriced:

1.There have been no showings for three weeks.

2.You haven’t had a single offer after 10 showings.

If you have any questions or need more information about all things real estate, please feel free to contact me. I’m more than happy to help you with your real estate needs, and I look forward to speaking with you soon!  
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+to+Tell+When+a+Listing+Is+Overpriced.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+to+Tell+When+a+Listing+Is+Overpriced.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What can alert you to the fact that your home is overpriced? Find out in today’s message.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What can alert you to the fact that your home is overpriced? Find out in today’s message.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Real Estate Trends to Know in 2019</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-real-estate-trends-to-know-in-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-28 13:23:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+4+Trends+to+Watch+for+in+2019.mp4</guid>
        <description>

To start off 2019 right, we’re going to share four key trends that buyers and sellers should keep an eye on this year:

1. There will be more homes for sale, especially in the luxury markets. For the past year, all we’ve been talking about is our low inventory levels. This past winter, we actually hit record lows. We’ve been joking that there are more Realtors out there than there are homes for sale right now. With all that said, we should expect to see inventory increase this year. With a modest slowdown in buyer activity, we should see supply recover. Where we’re really going to see a difference is in the $500,000+ luxury market, which has already shifted to a bit of a buyer’s market.

“Millennials will still dominate the home buying market.”

2. Affording a home is going to become more difficult. In the fourth quarter of 2018, we saw an increase in mortgage interest rates. This has dipped back down since the beginning of the year and has held fairly steady since, but we can expect to see rates go up at least twice in 2019. When you couple this with increased home prices, affordability will drop, making it harder for buyers. As for sellers, the earlier you list, the better off you’re going to be. The same message goes for buyers.

3. Millennials will still dominate the home buying market. Millennials are now the largest demographic of homebuyers, making up 45% of mortgages. Expect that number to increase in 2019 as we see more and more first-time buyers.

4. The new tax law is still a wild card. Many people thought that last year’s tax reform would discourage home buying because of the increase in the standard deduction. However, we won’t really see that effect until people file their taxes in April. We should have some more answers on what this law will mean for our market in the next few months.

If you have any questions about any of these topics or about real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+4+Trends+to+Watch+for+in+2019.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+4+Trends+to+Watch+for+in+2019.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Recent trends in real estate paint a pretty clear picture of where our market is headed in 2019. Here are four such trends and what they mean for you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Recent trends in real estate paint a pretty clear picture of where our market is headed in 2019. Here are four such trends and what they mean for you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips for Investing in Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-for-investing-in-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-12 10:25:57 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+4+Strategies+for+Investing+in+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It’s no secret that investing in real estate is a great way to generate passive income and increase your wealth. Today, I want to share four strategies so that you can start investing in real estate, particularly if you are in your 20s and 30s.

1. House hacking. This is a great opportunity because most people’s first investment in real estate is their own primary residence. The basic concept of house hacking is that you buy a property and leverage some part of the property to create rental income to offset your housing costs. For example, you could buy a 2-bedroom condo and rent out a room. You could also buy a duplex and live in one side while renting out the other. That way, you get to experience being a landlord and property management while offsetting your housing costs.

2. Short-term rentals. You can purchase a property in hot tourist areas or vacation spots. Charging a premium during peak seasons will allow you to offset the cost of the down season. You can also use Airbnb to get your property in front of potential visitors. Just make sure you check for any zoning restrictions on Airbnb in your area.

“House hacking allows you to leverage your property to offset your housing costs.”

3. Real estate investment trusts. If being a landlord is not your style, consider investing in an REIT. Real estate investment trusts are basically like mutual funds; a group of people pools their money in order to buy real estate assets together. This way, you can be a stakeholder and invest in the real estate market without the full responsibility of owning one asset yourself. If you are interested in REITs, I recommend that you check in with a financial advisor first.

4. Financial reserves. Do you have financial reserves so that you can go a month without rent? Do you have enough money to maintain the property? If the washing machine, refrigerator, or air conditioner goes out, you need to be able to make those repairs. You need reserves to maintain the property in order to get a good return on your investment.

These tips and strategies will help you find investment opportunities in your 20s, 30s, and beyond. Just give me a call or send me an email if you have any questions. I would be happy to help you!

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+4+Strategies+for+Investing+in+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+4+Strategies+for+Investing+in+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re interested in investing in real estate, I have four strategies to help you get started.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re interested in investing in real estate, I have four strategies to help you get started.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Fall 2018 Market Update</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-fall-2018-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-29 10:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Our+Fall+2018+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

All year, we’ve been hearing themes in the news like “prices are going up,” “seller’s market,” “buyer demand,” “low inventory,” and so on. All of these signals seem to indicate that it’s a really good time to sell your home.

However, there are a couple factors that could disrupt this trajectory for those looking to buy or sell a home:

1. Mortgage rates have hit a seven-year high. Several weeks ago, the 30-year fixed-rate mortgage interest rate increase to 4.6%, the highest it’s been since 2011. This follows the same trajectory that we’ve seen over the course of the past year regarding increasing mortgage rates. Interestingly, mortgage applications spiked in September; this typically indicates that buyers think the rates will continue to go up, and based on other economic factors, we also predict that’s the case.

“A spike in mortgage applications typically indicates that buyers think the rates will continue to go up, and based on other economic factors, we also predict that’s the case.”

2. Affordability is dropping and buyer demand may follow. For someone who has a fixed monthly budget for their housing expenses, as housing prices and interest rates continue to rise, their buying power decreases. Where they were once able to buy a $250,000 home, they may no longer be able to afford that much anymore. If you’re trying to capitalize and get top dollar for your home, the time is now. 

3. More and more home sellers are reducing their prices. With the seasonality of our market, it’s to be expected that prices will come down in the late fall and into the winter. However, the combination of increased interest, decreased affordability, decreased demand, and sustained high prices is leading to what we would expect to see: a more dramatic decrease in values.

So what should we take away from this?

If you’re thinking about selling your home, you really shouldn’t wait to list. We can’t tell what’s going to happen over the next six months, so the time to act is now. For homebuyers, bear in mind that as those mortgage interest rates continue to rise, your buying power may decrease, so you should also consider acting quickly. Plus, who wouldn’t want to get into a new home before the new year?

If you have any questions about buying or selling in the current housing conditions we’re experiencing, feel free to give me a call.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Our+Fall+2018+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Our+Fall+2018+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s been going on in the market this fall, and what can we expect moving forward to winter?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s been going on in the market this fall, and what can we expect moving forward to winter?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6 Simple Things That Turn Off Potential Buyers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/6-simple-things-that-turn-off-potential-buyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-15 11:49:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+6+Turn-Offs+for+Potential+Buyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Before selling your home, make sure you have these six buyer turn-offs under control. Looking out for these will help your home get sold and keep potential buyers engrossed—not grossed out!

1. Moisture damage. 70% of homebuyers are put off by damp patches, moisture patches, and stained ceilings and walls. If you see any of these in your home, just roll on a fresh coat of paint.

2. Bad odor. 56% of homebuyers dislike odor in a home, whether it’s from pets, smoke, or other disagreeable smells. You can combat this with tools such as oil diffusers, candles, baked cookies, or even some simple Febreze.

3. Dull light. 54% of homebuyers reported that dull light is unattractive. Make sure burned-out bulbs are replaced, curtains and blinds are open, and you do anything else you can to avoid dullness. You want to frame your house in the best light possible!

“These are some important things to be aware of and consider.”

4. Cluttered rooms. 15% of buyers are disappointed by a cluttered room. The solution is simple: Clean up. It makes the house feel larger and removes distraction, helping the buyer feel they can make it their own.

5. Over-the-top decor. 14% report this as unappealing. While a certain style may work for you, you want buyers to see a house full of possibilities. Taking away the more outrageous decorations can help the imaginations of potential buyers run wild.

6. Outdated bathrooms. 25% of buyers disliked an out-of-date bathroom. Styles change, and what was popular in the ‘70s is not so much anymore. It can be to your advantage to remodel old-fashioned bathrooms and bring them forward to the modern day.

These are some important things to be aware of and consider, as they can make a huge difference in whether your home is sold or not. If you have questions or need further information, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to helping you.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+6+Turn-Offs+for+Potential+Buyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+6+Turn-Offs+for+Potential+Buyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You might have a great house to show, but these six things could make potential buyers turn and walk out the door.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You might have a great house to show, but these six things could make potential buyers turn and walk out the door.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Reasons to Consider Selling Your Home This Fall</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-reasons-to-consider-selling-your-home-this-fall.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-01 11:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Why+You+Should+Sell+Your+Home+in+the+Fall.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re getting into the cooler weather now, so I thought it would be a good time to talk about selling your home in the fall and a few of the benefits that it brings:

1. You have a more serious buyer pool to work with. In the spring and summer months, there are a lot of people with a lot of free time and a lot of houses on the market. There are plenty of buyers who are looking at homes that aren’t really serious about making a move. As you get into the fall months, the concentration of serious buyers is much higher. Most of these buyers want to get settled into a new home before the holiday season, so your buyer pool will be more willing to make an offer.

2. There’s less competition. The spring and summer months see a lot more homes on the market for sale, increasing competition among home sellers even in a seller’s market. As we move into the fall months, there are a lot of people who still need to buy before the end of the year. Many sellers take their homes off the market during this time, but if you’re still on the market you will have a stronger bargaining chip.

“Listing in the fall gives you much more flexibility as a home seller.”

3. Buyer demographics are different. In different seasons, you’ll see buyers with different needs. For example, in the spring or summer, a family may be looking to buy a home, but they have to close before school starts in August. In the fall, it might be a very different situation. You might have a younger buyer who sees a good opportunity or a corporate worker who’s is staying in a hotel until they are able to purchase a home. These different demographics create different motivations that can really become an advantage for you as a seller.

4. More flexibility for improvements. I can’t tell you how many sellers I’ve worked with who feel so much stress when it comes to getting their home ready for the market. They feel like they’re under the gun. If you’re selling in the fall, you have the entire summer to make sure your home looks its best when it hits the market. It gives you the flexibility to enjoy your summer and plan your improvements in advance.

These are just a few reasons why sellers should consider selling their home in the fall. If you have any questions for me in the meantime about selling your home or about the real estate market in general, don’t’ hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Why+You+Should+Sell+Your+Home+in+the+Fall.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Why+You+Should+Sell+Your+Home+in+the+Fall.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are plenty of reasons that you should consider selling your home in the fall. Here are four of the most attractive ones.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are plenty of reasons that you should consider selling your home in the fall. Here are four of the most attractive ones.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>These 5 Questions Will Help You Decide if You’re Really Ready to Buy</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/these-5-questions-will-help-you-decide-if-youre-really-ready-to-buy.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-14 14:40:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Questions+to+Ask+Yourself+Before+You+Buy+a+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are five helpful questions you can ask yourself to determine whether you’re ready to stop renting and buy a home:

1. Do you know how much you can afford? There are a lot of great online resources you can use to calculate a ballpark figure. Using an online mortgage calculator, for example, is a great way to find out what a mortgage will cost you. Keep in mind how much of a change this cost will be compared to your current living situation.

2. Do you have the down payment amount available? It’s a myth that you must put down at least 20% to buy a house. In fact, there are plenty of mortgage options out there that go as low as 0% financing. However, you should know what you are getting into when you agree to a mortgage loan and how your down payment amount will affect what your monthly mortgage costs. For example, the more you put down, the lower your monthly costs will be.

3. Will you have enough money left after closing? Make sure you are not completely liquidating your savings in order to buy your house. I recommend having three to six months’ worth of savings in reserve after you’ve covered your down payment and closing costs.

4. Is your credit in good shape/What does your debt look like? These questions refer to the conversations you’ll have with your lender before starting the pre-qualification or pre-approval process. If your credit is not in great shape and you have a high amount of debt, that will probably limit your purchasing power, so get these items sorted out first. A good lender will be able to help you do this and present you with strategies to either bring your credit up or reduce your debt load.

5. Where do you see yourself in the next couple of years? If you only plan on being in a particular area for a year or two, buying might not be the best option for you—you might still prefer the flexibility of renting. However, it is a good idea to do a cost-benefit analysis to know for sure. If it is going to cost you $1,500 to rent for two years but it will cost you $1,200 to buy a house, that might even things out. It all depends on what your investment in the property is going to be. If you plan on being in that area for three to five years, it definitely makes sense to go ahead and buy a home.

“Make sure you’re not completely liquidating your savings in order to buy your house.”

If you have any more questions about this topic or are thinking of buying or selling a home, please feel free to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Questions+to+Ask+Yourself+Before+You+Buy+a+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Questions+to+Ask+Yourself+Before+You+Buy+a+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are five questions you can ask yourself to decide if you are ready to buy a home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are five questions you can ask yourself to decide if you are ready to buy a home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Sellers Should Handle Multiple Offer Situations</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-sellers-should-handle-multiple-offer-situations.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-24 12:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+Sellers+Should+Handle+Multiple-Offer+Situations.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you have multiple offers to choose from as a seller, all the cards are in your hand from a negotiation standpoint. Yet the decision between these offers shouldn’t be made lightly. If you find yourself in this position, there are certain steps you should take when examining your choices to make sure that you select the best deal. The first thing you should do? Thank your agent for helping you into this position. After that, it’s time to consider the prices. This is a crucial aspect of each offer, but it shouldn’t cause you to dismiss all other factors. Look at all of your offers side by side and consider the different contingencies, timelines, and terms that are in play.

For example, if you’re moving across the country in 30 days, you will likely be interested in different contract terms than someone who’s just moving between neighborhoods. The amount of time the closing process will give you to move into your next home, per the terms of the offer, is an important point to consider. 

“Always have a thorough conversation with your agent about the terms and conditions of each offer you receive.”

You must look at the buyer’s financing terms. A cash offer and a financed offer will have different contingencies.

Also consider whether the buyer pre-approved or just pre-qualified? A pre-approved buyer should thought of as on the same tier as a cash buyer, since their offer is likely only contingent on an appraisal and appropriate title.

You need to also consider how much they are putting down for their earnest money deposit. With how fast things are moving in our market today, it isn’t uncommon to see buyers get cold feet. Earnest money is a good measure of a buyer’s commitment to a deal. And this is essential, because you don’t want to take your home off the market only to have the buyer back out after the inspection.

Finally, consider all contingencies. These can have a considerable impact on your transaction, so make sure you have a thorough conversation with your agent about the terms and conditions of each offer you receive. 

Remember: If your listing receives multiple offers, you hold the cards. You should negotiate the terms that best suit your goals. Just make sure that you don’t overlook anything when examining each contract.

If you have any additional questions about this or are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+Sellers+Should+Handle+Multiple-Offer+Situations.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+Sellers+Should+Handle+Multiple-Offer+Situations.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Previously I talked about multiple offer situations from the buyer's perspective. Today I am sharing things to consider from the seller's.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Previously I talked about multiple offer situations from the buyer's perspective. Today I am sharing things to consider from the seller's.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Rise Above the Competition as a Buyer</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-rise-above-the-competition-as-a-buyer.html</link>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-11 09:08:09 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+to+Rise+Above+the+Competition+as+a+Buyer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How should buyers navigate multiple offer situations in a seller’s market?

This is a very common scenario right now. In fact, I’ve worked with three different buyers in the last two weeks who have encountered a multiple offer situation.

Thankfully, there are ways you can be successful in standing out from among multiple offers. The key is to make your offer as attractive as possible, which can be achieved by implementing the following tips:

1. Submit a large earnest money deposit. In our market, it is common to see very low earnest money deposits. Therefore, submitting a larger one can go a long way in showing the seller how serious you are.

“I’ve worked with three different buyers in the last two weeks who have encountered a multiple offer situation.”

2. Show the seller you’re qualified. There’s a difference between a pre-qualification letter and a pre-approval letter. The latter is far more desirable in the eyes of the seller. But now, some banks are even doing what’s called a “pre-commitment” letter. This letter will make your offer look even more solid.

3. Give the seller time to move. Multiple offer situations can be just as overwhelming for sellers as they can be for buyers. So it’s important to be mindful of the seller’s needs when submitting an offer on their home. Allowing them a little extra time to arrange their transition between properties can make your offer more attractive.

4. Write your best offer. Unfortunately, buyers have much less room to negotiate when faced with multiple offer situations. With so many choices at their disposal, sellers feel less pressure to be accommodating. You may want to consider adding an executive summary to your offer. A clean, thorough, attractive offer will carry the greatest chance at success.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+to+Rise+Above+the+Competition+as+a+Buyer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+How+to+Rise+Above+the+Competition+as+a+Buyer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How should buyers handle multiple offer situations? Today I’ll explain four key strategies to follow.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How should buyers handle multiple offer situations? Today I’ll explain four key strategies to follow.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Now Is a Great Time to Sell in Our Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-now-is-a-great-time-to-sell-in-our-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Brad Cohen</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-13 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Why+Now+Is+a+Great+Time+to+Sell+in+Our+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Right now, the Harrisonburg and Rockingham County area is in a very strong seller’s market.

This means sellers can command top dollar for their properties because buyers have limited options to choose from and there is high competition between them. Inventory is the main reason we are in a seller’s market. Our total supply is around 365 available homes for sale, which is down 20 homes from the previous year and almost 100 compared to the year before that.

What does this mean for home values? Values have been rising and continue to rise based on the dwindling inventory levels. It is basic economics—as supply goes down, demand goes up, and so do prices.  

“Now is an opportune time to be a seller in our market.”

Interest rates have also been contributing to our market conditions. Over the past couple of years, they have been at historic low levels, but they have recently started climbing. Interestingly enough, though, they dropped again this past week. They were above 4.5%, but they have dropped back down to that level.

If you are a seller, this means you can buy or sell your property quickly and for top dollar. If you are a buyer, this means you need to be ready to make an offer when an available home comes along that meets your criteria. You also need to be able to see a home quickly once it hits the market.

If you have any other questions about our market or are thinking of buying or selling a home soon, please feel free to reach out to me. I would be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Why+Now+Is+a+Great+Time+to+Sell+in+Our+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brad+Cohen/Funkhouser+Real+Estate+Group-+Why+Now+Is+a+Great+Time+to+Sell+in+Our+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Inventory is low and home values are rising in our market. This means it is a great time to be a seller.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brad Cohen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Inventory is low and home values are rising in our market. This means it is a great time to be a seller.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Harrisonburg, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Brad Cohen</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Brad Cohen</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Harman Realty - your professional Harrisonburg Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
